Discover John... the angry youth, the musician, the radical, the husband,
the father, the lover, the idealist... through his own words
Imagine: John Lennon is a documentary, music film directed by Andrew Solt.
The biography of former Beatle, John Lennon—narrated by Lennon himself—with extensive material from Yoko Ono's personal collection, previously unseen
footage from Lennon's private archives, and interviews with David Bowie, his first wife Cynthia, second wife Yoko Ono and sons Julian and Sean.
Self (archive footage), played by John Lennon.
Self, played by Yoko Ono.
Self (archive footage), played by Paul McCartney.
Self (archive footage), played by George Harrison.
Self (archive footage), played by Ringo Starr.
Self, played by David Bowie.
Imagine: John Lennon is a 1988 documentary film directed by
Andrew Solt about English musician John Lennon.
It was released on 7 October 1988, two days before Lennon's 48th
birthday (and nearly eight years after his death).
The film chronicles Lennon's life and musical career as a
member of the Beatles and as a solo artist.
It features recordings that had not been released prior to the film: an acoustic demo of "Real Love" taped in 1979 (an alternate recording of which
would be finished by the Beatles for 1996's Anthology 2) and a rehearsal take of "Imagine" in mid-1971 before the final take was captured.
The film was commissioned by Yoko Ono in 1986.
None of the three former Beatles, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, or Ringo Starr, agreed
to participate in the film, though they reportedly mostly approved of it.
Imagine: John Lennon, with its wealth of archival footage and
narration, received generally positive reviews.
The film's soundtrack was also successful in the United States, reaching No.
31 on the charts and going gold.
Solt and Sam Egan authored a photo book of the same
title as a companion to the film.
The film explores themes of musician, archive footage, rock
singer, mass media, cult of personality.